Ingrid Fuentes

New Rochelle, NY 10804 | 917-620-4558 | ingridfmelgar@gmail.com <u>Github</u> | <u>Blogs</u> | <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Portfolio</u>

FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Software Engineer with working knowledge of Ruby on Rails and JavaScript/React/Redux based programming. Familiar with Data Structures. Background in business administration with experience in account management and working directly with clients. That has helped me to have a strong attention to details, and deal with clients in the languages I am fluent, Spanish, Catalan and English. I am also fluent in Italian. Developing my last project, Interview Tracker, helped me to accomplish the creation of the application the way I wanted adding extra components before the deadline.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Rails, SQL, JavaScript, React, Redux, PostgresQL, RESTful, APIs, Bootstrap, Firebase, Cloud Firestore. Object-oriented programming. I'm excited to learn new technologies.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Interview Tracker - Github | Demo

I created a single page React web app with a Rails API for individuals who want to keep track of their job applications

- App built with Rails as a backend and JavaScript, React.js and Redux as front-end. Used sessions to store user's data
- PostgreSQL as a database
- Bootstrap, HTML, CSS to style the website

Choco Gourmet- Chocolate Store - Github | Demo

Chocolate store where a user can buy their favorite chocolates online

- Used rails as a backend and vanilla JavaScript. Also, HTML, CSS
- SQLite to keep track of data
- Utilized localStorage to store encrypted user information client-side

Sabores del Mundo-Recipe Finder - Github | Demo

Recipe finder. A user can find other user's recipes and can create their own recipes

- App built with Rails. RESTful API for users to save their recipes. Utilized BCRYPT to store encrypted user information for security
- Database using SQLite
- Added HTML and CSS

EDUCATION

Flatiron SchoolFull Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program
New York City, NY
06/2019 - 05/2020

University of Barcelona Barcelona, Spain Bachelor in Business Administration 02/2009 - 06/2014

EXPERIENCE

OPEN WATER ACCELERATOR

Software Engineer Intern

New York, USA

Web development. Front-end using Javascript and React is

09/2020 - 12/2020

- Work closely with the Front-end team to make sure the user's experience is efficient
- Coordinate with the team to make the work on time in an efficient way and keep the code clean

ATC TORREALDAY

Accounting Associate

Barcelona, Spain 09/2013 - 08/2015

- Prepared invoices, managed clients accounts, and prepared reports for firm Accountants
- Communicated with clients via email and phone to handle account-related requests
- Clarified accounting issues with auditors and account managers